Nafisa Ali Amir

3601 Greenway Unit 503, Baltimore, Maryland, 21218, USA

Mobile: +1 443 635 7255 • Email: amirnafisa@gmail.com • Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/amirnafisa

SUMMARY

Software Engineer

Computer science student with diverse background and rich experience in industry, research and academia. A Machine learning and deep learning enthusiast, able to work both independently and in a team, demonstrating motivation and multi-tasking abilities required to meet demanding deadlines while maintaining highest standards

EDUCATION

Masters in Science and Engineering, Computer Science, Johns Hopkins University	2018-2020
Masters in Technology, Electronics Design and Tech, Indian Institute of Science	2010-2012
Bachelors in Engineering, Electronics and Telecommunication, Rajiv Gandhi Institute	2006-2010

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python • C • C++ • Perl • PyTorch • Numpy • Github • Microsoft Office • SVN

COURSES

Machine Learning • Deep Learning • Natural Language Processing • Probability and Statistics Data structures • Computational Genomics • Algorithms • Processor Design • Parallel Programming

PROJECTS

Github: https://github.com/amirnafisa

•	Food classification using Inception-v3 and Resnet	Nov 2018
•	Classification on MNIST and Fashion MNIST dataset	Aug 2018
•	Earley Parsing and HMM based Tagging using Forward Backward and Viterbi Algorithm	Sep 2018
•	Cyber Physical System with Service Oriented Architecture	Aug 2012

PUBLICATION

Rao, I. H., Amir, N. A., Dagale, H., & Kuri, J. (2012, December). e-SURAKSHAK: A cyber-physical healthcare system with service oriented architecture. In Electronic System Design (ISED), 2012 International Symposium on (pp. 177-182). IEEE.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Associate, PRIME and APT, University of Manchester, Manchester, UK

Jun 2016 – Feb 2017

- The project was a part of PRIME in collaboration with Intel, Microsoft Research, University of Southampton
- Developed verification applications for supporting spiking neural network applications
- Created embedded applications on the ARM based microprocessor (Cortex M4) for testing and benchmark validations

Research Student, Indian Institute of Science, Bengaluru, India

June 2011-May2012

- Worked on cyber physical healthcare systems with service oriented architecture
- It was designed, implemented and tested for nearby hospitals. The work was published by IEEE at International Symposium of Embedded Computing and System Design in December 2012

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Firmware Engineer, Automata Technologies, London, UK

Jan 2018 - Apr 2018

- Worked with commercial robot arm Eva built at the startup to imporove productivity
- Main tasks included firmware design and testing of robot's end effector

Design and Testing Engineer, Roamworks, Dubai, UAE

Aug 2014 - Jun 2016

- Designed product for scada and fleet management systems from design specification to mass production
- Worked with multiple industry standards protocols like HART, Modbus, Profibus, CANbus in scada and nonscada systems, provided hardware system solutions to the fleet management, monitoring and tracking systems

ASIC Design Engineer, Nvidia, Bengaluru, India

Aug 2012 - Feb 2014

- Major tasks included netlist verification and timing closure of CPUs and SOCs of Tegra processors
- Implemented engineering change orders (ECOs) on pre and post layout netlist